[
    [
        {
            "question": "In hydrogen atom transition to ground state:",
            "options": [
                "kinetic energy decreases, potential energy increases but total remains same",
                "kinetic energy increases, potential and total decrease",
                "kinetic and total decrease, potential increases",
                "kinetic, potential and total energy decrease"
            ],
            "correctOption": "kinetic energy increases, potential and total decrease",
            "id": 37
        },
        {
            "question": "A body in SHM with 10 cm amplitude is tripled in velocity at 5 cm displacement. New amplitude\u00b2 is:",
            "options": [
                "100",
                "400",
                "700",
                "500"
            ],
            "correctOption": "700",
            "id": 19
        },
        {
            "question": "Statement I: Adding heat raises temp. Statement II: Positive work done increases volume.",
            "options": [
                "Statement I is true but Statement II is false",
                "Both Statements are true",
                "Both Statements are false",
                "Statement I is false but Statement II is true"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Statement I is false but Statement II is true",
            "id": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Moment of inertia of a semicircular ring about axis through center perpendicular to plane is xMR\u00b2. Find x:",
            "options": [
                "4",
                "1",
                "6",
                "2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1",
            "id": 7
        },
        {
            "question": "Photoelectric threshold wavelength is 380 nm. With 260 nm, KE is:",
            "options": [
                "1.5 eV",
                "15.1 eV",
                "4.5 eV",
                "3.0 eV"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1.5 eV",
            "id": 38
        },
        {
            "question": "Green light (5303 \u00c5) in double slit gives how many bright fringes between minima:",
            "options": [
                "10",
                "04",
                "09",
                "05"
            ],
            "correctOption": "05",
            "id": 35
        },
        {
            "question": "A car accelerates uniformly from rest and covers a distance of 100 m in 5 s. Its acceleration is:",
            "options": [
                "8 m/s\u00b2",
                "10 m/s\u00b2",
                "5 m/s\u00b2",
                "6 m/s\u00b2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "8 m/s\u00b2",
            "id": 21
        },
        {
            "question": "The dimensional formula for pressure is:",
            "options": [
                "ML\u207b\u00b9T\u207b\u00b2",
                "MLT\u207b\u00b2",
                "ML\u00b2T\u207b\u00b2",
                "M\u207b\u00b9L\u207b\u00b9T\u207b\u00b2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "ML\u207b\u00b9T\u207b\u00b2",
            "id": 23
        },
        {
            "question": "Which law states that the net external torque on a system is equal to the rate of change of angular momentum?",
            "options": [
                "Newton's First Law",
                "Conservation of Angular Momentum",
                "Newton\u2019s Second Law for Rotation",
                "Kepler's Second Law"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Newton\u2019s Second Law for Rotation",
            "id": 25
        },
        {
            "question": "A vector of magnitude 10 units makes an angle of 60\u00b0 with the x-axis. Its y-component is:",
            "options": [
                "10\u221a3/2",
                "10/2",
                "5\u221a3",
                "5"
            ],
            "correctOption": "10\u221a3/2",
            "id": 22
        },
        {
            "question": "Eye is modeled as a refracting surface. Distance from surface for focus is:",
            "options": [
                "3.1 cm",
                "4.0 cm",
                "1 cm",
                "2 cm"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3.1 cm",
            "id": 33
        },
        {
            "question": "Two projectiles A and B are thrown at 40 m/s and 60 m/s at angles 30\u00b0 and 60\u00b0. The ratio of their ranges is:",
            "options": [
                "4 : 9",
                "2 : 3",
                "1 : 1",
                "3 : 2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "4 : 9",
            "id": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Four particles A, B, C, D have same momentum. Which has max kinetic energy?",
            "options": [
                "D",
                "C",
                "A",
                "B"
            ],
            "correctOption": "A",
            "id": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "A particle of mass 500 g has velocity (2t i + 3t\u00b2 j) m/s. Force at t=1s is (i + xj). Find x:",
            "options": [
                "4",
                "3",
                "6",
                "2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3",
            "id": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "A charged particle enters a magnetic field perpendicular to its velocity. The path of the particle is:",
            "options": [
                "Circular",
                "Linear",
                "Parabolic",
                "Elliptical"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Circular",
            "id": 47
        },
        {
            "question": "In an LCR series circuit, the resonance frequency is given by:",
            "options": [
                "1/(2\u03c0\u221a(LC))",
                "1/(2\u03c0RC)",
                "1/(2\u03c0LR)",
                "1/(LC)"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1/(2\u03c0\u221a(LC))",
            "id": 48
        },
        {
            "question": "In SHM, when displacement is 1/3 amplitude, total energy to KE ratio is x/8. x is:",
            "options": [
                "9",
                "6",
                "2",
                "7"
            ],
            "correctOption": "9",
            "id": 18
        },
        {
            "question": "A solid conducting sphere with charge Q is surrounded by an uncharged conducting hollow shell. If shell is given charge \u20134Q, the new potential difference is:",
            "options": [
                "4 V",
                "V",
                "2 V",
                "\u20132 V"
            ],
            "correctOption": "V",
            "id": 27
        },
        {
            "question": "Temp of gas is -78\u00b0C and avg KE is k. Temp for avg KE = 2k is:",
            "options": [
                "117",
                "320",
                "160",
                "-157"
            ],
            "correctOption": "117",
            "id": 13
        },
        {
            "question": "A radioactive substance has a half-life of 10 days. In how many days will only 1/8th of the substance remain?",
            "options": [
                "30",
                "20",
                "40",
                "10"
            ],
            "correctOption": "30",
            "id": 49
        },
        {
            "question": "Engine between boiling and freezing points of water. Efficiency:",
            "options": [
                "2, 3 and 4 only",
                "2 and 3 only",
                "2 and 4 only",
                "1 and 2 only"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2 and 4 only",
            "id": 14
        },
        {
            "question": "Weight of a body on Earth is 400 N. At half Earth's radius depth, it will be:",
            "options": [
                "200 N",
                "300 N",
                "100 N",
                "Zero"
            ],
            "correctOption": "200 N",
            "id": 6
        },
        {
            "question": "A long straight wire carries a current of 10 A. The magnetic field at a distance of 2 cm from the wire is:",
            "options": [
                "1 \u00d7 10\u207b\u2075 T",
                "10\u207b\u2076 T",
                "1 \u00d7 10\u207b\u2074 T",
                "10\u207b\u2077 T"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1 \u00d7 10\u207b\u2074 T",
            "id": 46
        },
        {
            "question": "If wire length doubled and cross-section halved, Young's modulus becomes:",
            "options": [
                "Y/4",
                "4Y",
                "Y",
                "2Y"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Y",
            "id": 9
        },
        {
            "question": "Heavy nucleus breaks into two. If velocity ratio is 8:27, radius ratio is:",
            "options": [
                "3:2",
                "2:3",
                "4:9",
                "8:27"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3:2",
            "id": 36
        },
        {
            "question": "AC cannot be measured by DC ammeter because:",
            "options": [
                "A.C cannot pass",
                "A.C changes direction",
                "Avg value is zero",
                "D.C. ammeter gets damaged"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Avg value is zero",
            "id": 44
        },
        {
            "question": "Two forces A and A/2 are perpendicular. Resultant magnitude is:",
            "options": [
                "(\u221a5)A/2",
                "5A/2",
                "(\u221a5)A\u00b2/2",
                "(\u221a5)A/4"
            ],
            "correctOption": "(\u221a5)A/2",
            "id": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Needles of ferro-, para- and diamagnetic materials react to magnet by:",
            "options": [
                "attract N1 strongly, N2 weakly and repel N3 weakly",
                "attract all three",
                "attract N1 and N2 strongly but repel N3",
                "attract N1 strongly, but repel N2 and N3 weakly"
            ],
            "correctOption": "attract N1 strongly, N2 weakly and repel N3 weakly",
            "id": 41
        },
        {
            "question": "A body cools from 80\u00b0C to 60\u00b0C in 5 min. Room temp is 20\u00b0C. Time to cool from 60\u00b0C to 40\u00b0C:",
            "options": [
                "500 s",
                "25 / 3 s",
                "450 s",
                "420 s"
            ],
            "correctOption": "500 s",
            "id": 11
        },
        {
            "question": "Radioactive source gives 1600 cps at t=0, 100 cps at t=8s. At t=6s it gives:",
            "options": [
                "250",
                "360",
                "150",
                "200"
            ],
            "correctOption": "200",
            "id": 40
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question": "The metal that cannot be obtained by electrolysis of an aqueous solution of its salt is",
            "options": [
                "Cr",
                "Ca",
                "Ag",
                "Cu"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ca",
            "id": 27
        },
        {
            "question": "The incorrect postulates of the Dalton's atomic theory are:",
            "options": [
                "Atoms of different elements differ in mass.",
                "Matter consists of divisible atoms.",
                "Compounds are formed when atoms of different element combine in a fixed ratio.",
                "Chemical reactions involve reorganisation of atoms."
            ],
            "correctOption": "Matter consists of divisible atoms.",
            "id": 37
        },
        {
            "question": "Statement I: Fluorine has most negative electron gain enthalpy in its group. Statement II: Oxygen has least negative electron gain enthalpy in its group.",
            "options": [
                "BOTH I AND II ARE TRUE",
                "BOTH I AND II ARE FALSE",
                "I IS TRUE BUT II IS FALSE",
                "II IS TRUE BUT I IS FALSE"
            ],
            "correctOption": "II IS TRUE BUT I IS FALSE",
            "id": 40
        },
        {
            "question": "The IUPAC name of CH3COCH(CH3)2 is",
            "options": [
                "3-methyl-2-butanone",
                "2-methyl-3-butanone",
                "4-methylisopropyl ketone",
                "Isopropylmethyl ketone"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3-methyl-2-butanone",
            "id": 21
        },
        {
            "question": "Which compound will not give silver mirror with ammoniacal AgNO3?",
            "options": [
                "Formic acid",
                "Formaldehyde",
                "Benzaldehyde",
                "Acetone"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Acetone",
            "id": 20
        },
        {
            "question": "From the following statements regarding H2O2, choose the incorrect statement",
            "options": [
                "It can act only as an oxidizing agent",
                "It has to be stored in plastic or wax-lined glass bottles in the dark",
                "It has to be kept away from dust",
                "It decomposes on exposure to light"
            ],
            "correctOption": "It can act only as an oxidizing agent",
            "id": 26
        },
        {
            "question": "At constant temperature, a gas is at a pressure of 940.3 mm Hg. The pressure at which its volume decreases by 40% is __________ mm Hg.",
            "options": [
                "1567",
                "1600",
                "2000",
                "3527"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1567",
            "id": 38
        },
        {
            "question": "Fusion of MnO2 with KOH and an oxidising agent gives dark green K2MnO4. Manganate ion on electrolytic oxidation in alkaline medium gives permanganate ion.",
            "options": [
                "BOTH I AND II ARE TRUE",
                "BOTH I AND II ARE FALSE",
                "I IS TRUE BUT II IS FALSE",
                "II IS TRUE BUT I IS FALSE"
            ],
            "correctOption": "II IS TRUE BUT I IS FALSE",
            "id": 5
        },
        {
            "question": "The incorrect statements regarding enzymes are:",
            "options": [
                "Enzymes are bio catalysts.",
                "Enzymes are non-specific and cannot catalyse different kinds of reactions.",
                "Most enzymes are globular proteins.",
                "Enzyme - oxidase catalyses the hydrolysis of maltose into glucose."
            ],
            "correctOption": "Enzyme - oxidase catalyses the hydrolysis of maltose into glucose.",
            "id": 10
        },
        {
            "question": "Coagulation of egg on heating is because of:",
            "options": [
                "Denaturation of protein occurs.",
                "Biological properties of proteins remain unchanged",
                "Breaking of peptide linkage in the primary structure of protein occurs",
                "The secondary structure of protein remains unchanged"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Denaturation of protein occurs.",
            "id": 6
        },
        {
            "question": "The element having the highest first ionization enthalpy is",
            "options": [
                "C",
                "Al",
                "N",
                "Si"
            ],
            "correctOption": "N",
            "id": 39
        },
        {
            "question": "p-nitrophenol is more acidic than m- and o-nitrophenol. Ethanol will give immediate turbidity with Lucas reagent.",
            "options": [
                "BOTH I AND II ARE TRUE",
                "BOTH I AND II ARE FALSE",
                "II IS TRUE BUT I IS FALSE",
                "I IS TRUE BUT II IS FALSE"
            ],
            "correctOption": "I IS TRUE BUT II IS FALSE",
            "id": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "Chlorine water on standing loses its colour and forms:",
            "options": [
                "HCl and HClO2",
                "HCl only",
                "HOCl and HOCl2",
                "HCl and HOCl"
            ],
            "correctOption": "HCl and HOCl",
            "id": 30
        },
        {
            "question": "Find the volume of 1 g of H2 gas in litres at N.T.P",
            "options": [
                "11.2",
                "22.4",
                "2.24",
                "112"
            ],
            "correctOption": "11.2",
            "id": 31
        },
        {
            "question": "Acidity of \u03b1-hydrogens of aldehydes and ketones is responsible for Aldol reaction. Benzaldehyde and ethanal will not give Cross-Aldol product.",
            "options": [
                "BOTH I AND II ARE TRUE",
                "BOTH I AND II ARE FALSE",
                "I IS TRUE BUT II IS FALSE",
                "II IS TRUE BUT I IS FALSE"
            ],
            "correctOption": "I IS TRUE BUT II IS FALSE",
            "id": 19
        },
        {
            "question": "Which one of the following substances has the highest proton affinity?",
            "options": [
                "H2S",
                "NH3",
                "PH3",
                "H2O"
            ],
            "correctOption": "NH3",
            "id": 32
        },
        {
            "question": "Phenol treated with chloroform in presence of sodium hydroxide, then hydrolyzed in acid results in:",
            "options": [
                "2-Hydroxybenzaldehyde",
                "Salicylic Acid",
                "quinol",
                "Benzene-1,2-diol"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2-Hydroxybenzaldehyde",
            "id": 11
        },
        {
            "question": "\u2206U is equal to",
            "options": [
                "adiabatic work",
                "isothermal work",
                "isochoric work",
                "isobaric work"
            ],
            "correctOption": "adiabatic work",
            "id": 33
        },
        {
            "question": "The gas liberated by the electrolysis of Dipotassium succinate solution is:",
            "options": [
                "Ethyne",
                "Propene",
                "Ethane",
                "Ethene"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ethene",
            "id": 25
        },
        {
            "question": "Determine the total number of neutrons in three isotopes of hydrogen",
            "options": [
                "1",
                "2",
                "3",
                "4"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3",
            "id": 29
        },
        {
            "question": "The molecular formula of second homologue in the mono carboxylic acids series is:",
            "options": [
                "C2H2O4",
                "C2H2O2",
                "CH2O",
                "C3H6O2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "C2H2O4",
            "id": 18
        },
        {
            "question": "The process with negative entropy change is",
            "options": [
                "dissolution of iodine in water",
                "sublimation of dry ice",
                "synthesis of ammonia from N2 and H2",
                "dissociation of CaSO4(s) to CaO(s) and SO3(g)"
            ],
            "correctOption": "synthesis of ammonia from N2 and H2",
            "id": 34
        },
        {
            "question": "Haloalkanes react with KCN to form alkyl cyanides, but with AgCN form isocyanides. KCN and AgCN are highly ionic compounds.",
            "options": [
                "BOTH I AND II ARE TRUE",
                "BOTH I AND II ARE FALSE",
                "I IS TRUE BUT II IS FALSE",
                "II IS TRUE BUT I IS FALSE"
            ],
            "correctOption": "I IS TRUE BUT II IS FALSE",
            "id": 14
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following has the highest number of unpaired electrons?",
            "options": [
                "Sc",
                "Cr",
                "V",
                "Ti"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Cr",
            "id": 7
        },
        {
            "question": "Which nitrogen compound does not give Lassaigne's test?",
            "options": [
                "Hydrazine",
                "Urea",
                "Glycene",
                "Phenyl Hydrazine"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Hydrazine",
            "id": 16
        },
        {
            "question": "The IUPAC name of CH3CHO is",
            "options": [
                "Acetaldehyde",
                "Ethanal",
                "Methyl aldehyde",
                "Ethanol"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ethanal",
            "id": 22
        },
        {
            "question": "High concentration of strong nucleophilic reagent with secondary alkyl halides will follow SN2 mechanism. Secondary alkyl halide with excess ethanol follows SN1 mechanism.",
            "options": [
                "BOTH I AND II ARE TRUE",
                "BOTH I AND II ARE FALSE",
                "I IS TRUE BUT II IS FALSE",
                "II IS TRUE BUT I IS FALSE"
            ],
            "correctOption": "BOTH I AND II ARE TRUE",
            "id": 13
        },
        {
            "question": "The higher oxidation states are more stable down the group among transition elements unlike p-block elements. Copper cannot liberate hydrogen from weak acids.",
            "options": [
                "BOTH I AND II ARE TRUE",
                "BOTH I AND II ARE FALSE",
                "I IS TRUE BUT II IS FALSE",
                "II IS TRUE BUT I IS FALSE"
            ],
            "correctOption": "BOTH I AND II ARE TRUE",
            "id": 8
        },
        {
            "question": "The vapor pressure of pure benzene and methyl benzene at 27\u00b0C is given as 80 Torr and 24 Torr, respectively. The mole fraction of methyl benzene in vapor phase, in equilibrium with an equimolar mixture of those two liquids is:",
            "options": [
                "0.23",
                "0.89",
                "0.99",
                "0.73"
            ],
            "correctOption": "0.23",
            "id": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The alkene that exhibits geometrical isomerism is:",
            "options": [
                "2\u2013methyl\u20132\u2013butene",
                "Propene",
                "2\u2013butene",
                "2\u2013methylpropene"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2\u2013butene",
            "id": 24
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question": "What is the sum of the angles in a triangle?",
            "options": [
                "180\u00c2\u00b0",
                "360\u00c2\u00b0",
                "90\u00c2\u00b0",
                "270\u00c2\u00b0"
            ],
            "correctOption": "180\u00c2\u00b0",
            "id": 7
        },
        {
            "question": "Let f(x) be a quadratic polynomial such that f(-2) + f(3) = 0. If one of the roots of f(x) = 0 is 1, then the sum of the roots of f(x) = 0 is equal to:",
            "options": [
                "3",
                "13/3",
                "35/3",
                "11/3"
            ],
            "correctOption": "11/3",
            "id": 50
        },
        {
            "question": "In an increasing geometric progression... the sum of the 4th, 6th and 8th terms is equal to:",
            "options": [
                "45",
                "91",
                "76",
                "50"
            ],
            "correctOption": "91",
            "id": 42
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the quadratic formula?",
            "options": [
                "x = (-b \u00c2\u00b1 \u00e2\u02c6\u0161(b\u00c2\u00b2 - 4ac)) / 2a",
                "x = (b \u00c2\u00b1 \u00e2\u02c6\u0161(b\u00c2\u00b2 - 4ac)) / 2a",
                "x = (-b \u00c2\u00b1 \u00e2\u02c6\u0161(b\u00c2\u00b2 + 4ac)) / 2a",
                "x = (b \u00c2\u00b1 \u00e2\u02c6\u0161(b\u00c2\u00b2 + 4ac)) / 2a"
            ],
            "correctOption": "x = (-b \u00c2\u00b1 \u00e2\u02c6\u0161(b\u00c2\u00b2 - 4ac)) / 2a",
            "id": 8
        },
        {
            "question": "Let S = {1, 2, 3, 5, 7, 10, 11}. The number of non-empty subsets of S that have the sum of all elements a multiple of 3, is _____________.",
            "options": [
                "45",
                "20",
                "35",
                "43"
            ],
            "correctOption": "43",
            "id": 25
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the derivative of sin(x)?",
            "options": [
                "cos(x)",
                "-sin(x)",
                "-cos(x)",
                "sin(x)"
            ],
            "correctOption": "cos(x)",
            "id": 19
        },
        {
            "question": "The number of relations... which are reflexive and transitive but not symmetric, is __________.",
            "options": [
                "1",
                "2",
                "3",
                "5"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3",
            "id": 44
        },
        {
            "question": "The number of solutions of sin3x = cos 2x, in the interval (90,180) is :",
            "options": [
                "4",
                "7",
                "3",
                "1"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1",
            "id": 35
        },
        {
            "question": "If sin A + cos A = \u00bd , then 16(sin(2A) + cos(4A) + sin(6A)) is equal to :",
            "options": [
                "45",
                "-23",
                "35",
                "43"
            ],
            "correctOption": "-23",
            "id": 52
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the solution to the equation x^2 - 4 = 0?",
            "options": [
                "x = \u00c2\u00b12",
                "x = 2",
                "x = -2",
                "x = 0"
            ],
            "correctOption": "x = \u00c2\u00b12",
            "id": 18
        },
        {
            "question": "The portion of the line 4x+5y=20 in the first quadrant is trisected by the lines P and Q passing through the origin. The tangent of an angle between the lines P and Q is :",
            "options": [
                "45",
                "30/41",
                "35/41",
                "43/7"
            ],
            "correctOption": "30/41",
            "id": 57
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the derivative of x^2?",
            "options": [
                "2x",
                "x^2",
                "x",
                "2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "2x",
            "id": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Let S = {1, 2, 3, 5, 7, 10, 11}. The number of non-empty subsets of S that have the sum of all elements a multiple of 3, is _____________.",
            "options": [
                "45",
                "20",
                "35",
                "43"
            ],
            "correctOption": "43",
            "id": 45
        },
        {
            "question": "A variable line L passes through the point (3,5)... The minimum area of the triangle OAB , where O is the origin, is",
            "options": [
                "30",
                "23",
                "35",
                "43"
            ],
            "correctOption": "30",
            "id": 56
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the value of cos(180\u00c2\u00b0)?",
            "options": [
                "-1",
                "1",
                "0",
                "0.5"
            ],
            "correctOption": "-1",
            "id": 16
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the value of e^0?",
            "options": [
                "1",
                "0",
                "e",
                "-1"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1",
            "id": 9
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the sum of the first n natural numbers?",
            "options": [
                "n(n+1)/2",
                "n^2",
                "n(n-1)/2",
                "n^2 + n"
            ],
            "correctOption": "n(n+1)/2",
            "id": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "A circle is inscribed in an equilateral triangle of side of length 12... then m+n^2 is equal to",
            "options": [
                "900",
                "470",
                "408",
                "488"
            ],
            "correctOption": "408",
            "id": 39
        },
        {
            "question": "In an increasing geometric progression... the sum of the 4th, 6th and 8th terms is equal to:",
            "options": [
                "45",
                "91",
                "76",
                "50"
            ],
            "correctOption": "91",
            "id": 22
        },
        {
            "question": "The equation y = sinx sin (x + 2) \u2013 sin^2 (x + 1) represents a straight line lying in :",
            "options": [
                "III and IV QUADRANTS",
                "II and IV QUADRANTS",
                "I, III and IV QUADRANTS",
                "II,III and IV QUADRANTS"
            ],
            "correctOption": "III and IV QUADRANTS",
            "id": 53
        },
        {
            "question": "A software company sets up m number of computer systems... then it took 8 more days to finish the assignment. The value of m is equal to:",
            "options": [
                "150",
                "220",
                "135",
                "250"
            ],
            "correctOption": "150",
            "id": 43
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the slope of the line y = 3x + 2?",
            "options": [
                "3",
                "2",
                "-3",
                "-2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3",
            "id": 10
        },
        {
            "question": "The number of solutions of the equation x + 2tanx = \u03c0/2 in the interval [0, 2\u03c0] is :",
            "options": [
                "9",
                "7",
                "3",
                "4"
            ],
            "correctOption": "3",
            "id": 54
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the integral of 2x dx?",
            "options": [
                "x^2 + C",
                "2x + C",
                "x^2",
                "2x"
            ],
            "correctOption": "x^2 + C",
            "id": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If sin A + cos A = \u00bd , then 16(sin(2A) + cos(4A) + sin(6A)) is equal to :",
            "options": [
                "45",
                "-23",
                "35",
                "43"
            ],
            "correctOption": "-23",
            "id": 32
        },
        {
            "question": "A variable line L passes through the point (3,5)... The minimum area of the triangle OAB , where O is the origin, is",
            "options": [
                "30",
                "23",
                "35",
                "43"
            ],
            "correctOption": "30",
            "id": 36
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the area of a circle with radius r?",
            "options": [
                "\u00cf\u20acr^2",
                "2\u00cf\u20acr",
                "\u00cf\u20acr",
                "r^2"
            ],
            "correctOption": "\u00cf\u20acr^2",
            "id": 11
        },
        {
            "question": "The number of integers between 100 and 1000 having the sum of their digits equals to 14 , is _________",
            "options": [
                "45",
                "70",
                "35",
                "43"
            ],
            "correctOption": "70",
            "id": 47
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the value of sin(90\u00c2\u00b0)?",
            "options": [
                "1",
                "0",
                "-1",
                "0.5"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1",
            "id": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "The equation y = sinx sin (x + 2) \u2013 sin^2 (x + 1) represents a straight line lying in :",
            "options": [
                "III and IV QUADRANTS",
                "II and IV QUADRANTS",
                "I, III and IV QUADRANTS",
                "II,III and IV QUADRANTS"
            ],
            "correctOption": "III and IV QUADRANTS",
            "id": 33
        }
    ]
]